<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
  <atom:link href="https://boundlessgarden.tulloch.contact/files/rss/files/xml.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <title>RSS</title>
  <link>https://boundlessgarden.tulloch.contact</link>
  <description>Rss feed in tiddlywiki</description>
  <language>en-GB</language>
  <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 23:06:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
	<item>
      <title>RSS2</title>
      <description></description>
      <category>rss</category>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p>RSS, otherwise known as Really Simple Syndication, is a way of formatting feeds of information in a way that is simple for computers and humans alike to read. RSS has been around since 2009, and hasn't changed since 2009, meaning that it has widespread adoption across the web. They are commonly used by blogs, online news providers, and some social media services. <a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-resolves tc-popup-handle tc-popup-absolute" href="https://boundlessgarden.tulloch.contact#Podcasts">Podcasts</a> also started entirely in RSS format.</p><p>RSS can be found anywhere where you see this <svg class="tc-image-rss2 tc-image-button" height="22pt" viewBox="0 0 16 16" width="22pt"><path d="M14.5 0h-13C.675 0 0 .675 0 1.5v13c0 .825.675 1.5 1.5 1.5h13c.825 0 1.5-.675 1.5-1.5v-13c0-.825-.675-1.5-1.5-1.5zM4.359 12.988c-.75 0-1.359-.603-1.359-1.353a1.36 1.36 0 0 1 2.718 0c0 .75-.609 1.353-1.359 1.353zM7.772 13a4.753 4.753 0 0 0-1.397-3.381A4.74 4.74 0 0 0 3 8.219V6.263c3.713 0 6.738 3.022 6.738 6.737H7.772zm3.472 0c0-4.547-3.697-8.25-8.241-8.25V2.794c5.625 0 10.203 4.581 10.203 10.206h-1.963z"></path></svg> icon, which normally is a direct link to the feed that you can copy and paste into your reader of choice, see <a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-missing" href="https://boundlessgarden.tulloch.contact#News">News</a> for more on that.</p><p>RSS great because it's tracking and cookie free - because it's text only none of the tools that can track you around the internet are actually able to load. It's ad free, so those horrible intrusive local news ads aren't a problem anymore. Finally it also works great for downloading articles to read offline - as they're only text they barely take up any space on your phone.</p><h3 class="">Writings on RSS</h3><p><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">RSS</a> - Wikipedia</p><p><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://pluralistic.net/2024/10/16/keep-it-really-simple-stupid/#read-receipts-are-you-kidding-me-seriously-fuck-that-noise" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">You should be using an RSS Reader</a> - Cory Doctorow</p><p><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://blog.amen6.com/blog/2025/01/no-shorts-please-hidden-youtube-rss-feed-urls/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">No Shorts Please! Hidden YouTube RSS Feed URLs</a> - Kenzeh</p><h3 class="">RSS Resources</h3><p><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://morss.it/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">morss.it</a> - Some websites don't serve their whole articles over RSS by default, so this is a great way of creating feeds that do.</p><h3 class="">Example Feeds</h3><p><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/10628494" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the BBC</a> - Ironically this wonderfully not-updated page includes links to articles from 2016 in the sidebar, looks like BBC's internal feeds broke but (most) of these feeds still work.</p><p><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULF99kO6xDZSh2UNA-jdpN7cA" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Mineatur Wunderland</a> - An example YouTube feed with shorts removed, as per the blog above.</p><p><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://www.late-review.com/feed" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">The Late Review</a> - An example Substack feed (newsletters don't actually need to clog up your inbox!)</p></p>]]></content:encoded>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 22:21:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>https://boundlessgarden.tulloch.contact#RSS2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://boundlessgarden.tulloch.contact#RSS2</guid>
   </item><item>
      <title>Podcasts</title>
      <description></description>
      <category>rss</category>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p>I've put podcasts first because this is an easy starting point to dip your toe in and see how it feels.</p><p><strong>Faff</strong>: 1/3 <em>(You may need to manually subscribe your podcasts if coming from a walled garden)</em></p><p><strong>Cost</strong>: 0-1/3 <em>(Free, with a paid option to remove ads in one case.)</em></p><h3 class="">Pre-waffle</h3><p>Podcasts are one of those areas that used to be completely the domain of the open internet, but ever since their explosion in the 2010's have been retreating further and further into walled gardens.</p><p>Spotify has spent <a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://www.theverge.com/21265005/spotify-joe-rogan-experience-podcast-deal-apple-gimlet-media-ringer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">over a billion dollars</a> on expanding it's market share and bringing listeners into its garden. If you're dedicated to their exclusives there's not much this guide can do for you, but for everyone else here's how to escape.</p><h3 class="">Step 1: What is a podcast?</h3><p>A podcast in it's original sense is simply an <a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-resolves tc-popup-handle tc-popup-absolute" href="https://boundlessgarden.tulloch.contact#RSS">RSS feed</a> that contains links to audio files. That's it. And that means that due to the incredible support for RSS across the web you can add any non-exclusive podcast to any RSS reader (see <a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-missing" href="https://boundlessgarden.tulloch.contact#News">News</a>) and get your podcasts that way, but those lack very useful features for podcasts like auto-downloaded and the like. </p><p>Any good podcast app will support OMPL import/export, which is a way of moving all of your subscriptions from one app to another freely. This is absolutely vital to making sure you don't get stuck in another walled garden. (Unsurprisingly spotify doesn't support this).</p><p>So that leads us to two apps. Both are very good, a lot better than spotify and <em>account free</em>. Pick which one suits you best!</p><h3 class="">Step 2a: The single best podcast app (for privacy)</h3><p><strong>AntennaPod</strong><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://antennapod.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://antennapod.org/</a></p><p>AntennaPod is a podcast app that does exactly what it does on the tin, and if you're looking to go full boundless-garden, the better option. Podcasts, really well. The app is <em>blazingly fast</em> looks good, and supports all the bare minimum features: auto-download, a queue, RSS &amp; OPML support. The app is completely open source and can be installed from alternative <a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-missing" href="https://boundlessgarden.tulloch.contact#App%20Stores">App Stores</a>.</p><h3 class="">Step 2b: The single best podcast app (if you're a control freak)</h3><p><strong>Podcast Addict</strong><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://podcastaddict.com/app" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://podcastaddict.com/app</a></p><p>First of all let's say what Podcast Addict isn't. It isn't ad free (unless you pay), it isn't open source, and it isn't completely <a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-missing" href="https://boundlessgarden.tulloch.contact#Algorithms">algorithm</a> free. Make sure to deny your consent to data collection when you install. However the ads and algorithms are very minimal, and it more than makes up in features.</p><p>It offers an incredible level of customisation, with each podcast having vast array of customisation options. I've got it setup so it automatically forms a queue, all my favourites at the top, followed by one episode each of podcasts I'm working through the backlog of, followed by a few manually added episodes from podcasts I only listen to some of. It's all manually downloaded and works flawlessly.</p><p>That said it can be quite overwhelming and can take a bit of time to setup, so if you're looking for something simpler I'd recommend AntennaPod.</p><h3 class="">Step 3: Get subscribing</h3><p>Once you've got your app of choice, all you've got to do is fill it up! Both AntennaPod and PodcastAddict have search engines to search for your podcasts to add. Also, most podcasts will have an RSS link on their website that will open directly in your podcast player of choice, or you can copy and paste the link into your app.</p><h3 class="">Conclusion</h3><p>You've moved yourself out of a walled garden into an app that you don't have to pay for, and is completely open. If these apps go downhill, or you feel like you might want to try something else, you're completely free to take your OPML file elsewhere.</p></p>]]></content:encoded>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 22:07:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>https://boundlessgarden.tulloch.contact#Podcasts</link>
      <guid isPermaLink='true'>https://boundlessgarden.tulloch.contact#Podcasts</guid>
   </item>
</channel>
</rss>